耳… 聴力を賭けたＥカード
Kaiji's sense of hearing is
being gambled in E-Card.
３戦 ４戦と利根川に連敗のカイジ
Kaiji lost the 3rd and 4th
game to Tonegawa in a row.
針は進む
The needle inches
closer everytime he loses.
And now the 5th game.
Kaiji needs a victory badly.
５戦目…
勝利への突破口が欲しいカイジ
Fear.
恐れ？
そうだ　恐れだ
That's it! Fear!
見えた
I can see it.
一筋の光明…
A streak of light!
Trifled
恐れ… それだけは利根川にも
絶対 あるはず
Fear. It's something even
Tonegawa should have.
ないはずがない
It's impossible for
him to be fearless.
なぜなら これはギャンブル
Because we're gambling.
ギャンブルとは
リスクを背負うこと
Gambling means risks.
恐れを抱くこと
And he has to fear losing!
俺はもちろん 利根川も必ず震える
I fear and so will he!
いよいよとなれば
恐れないはずがない
Truthfully, there's no way
anyone can avoid fear.
この心理戦
Ｅカードで突き詰めるべきは
E-Card's a psychological game.
I have to find the opponent's fear.
相手の恐れ 恐怖がどこにあるか…
The question is...
"how do i find out?".
見つけたい
見つければ それが足がかりになる
I've to find his fear.
It's easier to win that way.
しかし カイジには見えない
But Kaiji can't see it.
利根川は あまりにも
つかみどころがない
Tonegawa has too
few weak spots.
ならば 作る
Fine!
I'll create them then!
利根川の心に恐れの幻想を
I'll create a fear illusion
in Tonegawa's heart!
となると…
Which means...
やれやれ　やっと決めたか
At last, you've decided?
３分… ただ待つ３分は長いもんだ
3 minutes.
Waiting for 3 minutes
is quite long.
カイジ君には あっという間でもな
I know it seems
short for you, Kaiji.
いろいろ考えたのだろうが
下手な考え 何とやらだ
I know you're
trying to plan wisely,
but it seems you're
going in the wrong direction.
Ｅカードは大筋の思考の流れ
In E-Card, it'll be alright
as long as the overall...
動きを間違えなければ それでよし
...flow of thinking and
movements aren't mess up.
簡単な話さ
It's as simple as that.
利根川 あっさり選択 提出
Tonegawa chose and
placed his card with ease.
５戦目の２枚目 オープン
The 2nd card of
the 5th game.
Open!
カイジは｢奴隷｣
Kaiji's Slave.
４戦目と同じく
２枚目に再び｢奴隷｣
Like the 4th game,
he chose Slave as the 2nd card.
｢市民｣　利根川の勝ち
Citizen!
Tonegawa's win.
利根川 これで３連勝
Tonegawa 3rd
straight win.
ふふふ… それでは早速
Alright then.
Go!
３連敗…
3 straight losses.
何か戦略を思いついたかに
みえたカイジだったが
Any strategy Kaiji had,
failed him it seemed.
結局 負け
金は得られず ただ針だけが進む
Still no cash. But the
needle's moving again.
合計 14ミリ
A total of 14 mm.
徐々に暗雲… 暗雲立ちこめる
The dark clouds gather...
They gather!
ダメだ　勝てない
この人も負ける 利根川に…
It's useless.
He can't win.
That guy will lose
to Tonegawa.
利根川
Tonegawa.
Yes.
もう少し希望を持たせつつ
勝つわけにはいかんのか
Give him a little hope.
But make sure you still win.
あまり寄せつけない
勝ち方をすると
If you keep winning like this,
カイジ君が ほれ…
安全にいってしまう
Kaiji will opt
for the safe route.
勝負を捨ててな
He'll avoid going head on.
わしは それだけが心配でな
I'm worried
that will happen.
Oh.
カイジ様
次のベット 賭け距離は？
Mr. Kaiji, what is your next bet?
カイジ様？
Mr. Kaiji.
10…
10.
10だ
10!
次は10いく
I'll go with 10!
ほう
じゅ 10って… いいのか 本当に？
10?! Are you serious?
Are you sure?
余計なことを言うではない
Hey there,
we don't need your input.
お前は黙って ただ書けばいいのだ
Be quiet and
write it down.
カイジ君の気が変わらぬうちにな
Before Kaiji changes his mind.
は… はい
Yes!
This is fun. Fun!
愉快 愉快
利根川が ここで10ミリ勝てば
If Tonegawa wins,
Kaiji will lose 24 mm.
カイジの負けは24ミリ
残り試合 １ミリずつ張っても
Even if he bets
1 mm consecutively...
全敗すれば30ミリ
...and loses each time,
it will be 30mm.
破滅… 針が鼓膜を破る
Destruction! The needle
will pierce his eardrum!
あはは… 面白い
そういう勝負をしてくれてこそ
Interesting. I'm glad I stayed
for this overtime game...
この延長戦 夜更かしにも
意味があろうというもの
...when you gamble like that.
利根川
はい
Tonegawa.
Yes.
次は100パーセント 勝ちなさい
Win the next game 100%.
It should be easy for you.
たやすかろう
You have the advantage...
...because you're on
the Emperor side.
有利な皇帝側だ
よもや負けなどしまい
You can't lose.
Yes.
バカな… 何でここで10ミリ？
No way.
Why 10 mm here?
勝つ見込みの少ない奴隷側で…
He's on the Slave side
with no chance to win...
いくしかなかったんだ
There's no other way.
Huh?
He must do it now
to win big.
ここでいかないと
もう大勝はないから
このＥカードで まとまった金を
得ようとするならば
In E-Card, to win big, one must
bet a large amount and...
５倍返しの奴隷側で
厚く張って勝たねばならない
...win on the Slave side
with 5 times the return rate.
カイジはラスト３戦は奴隷側だが
Towards the end, Kaiji will
play the Slave side again.
その時には厚く張る距離が
残っていないかもしれない
And he might not have
much distance to bet then.
となると まだ張れる距離が
残っているこの６戦が
So while the needle is still
a considerable length away,
奴隷で厚く張るラストチャンス…
いくしかない
it's his last chance to
bet on the Slave side!
He has to do it!
ムチャを承知でか
So he knows what he's doing?
６戦目
The 6th game.
先出しは皇帝側の利根川
Tonegawa plays first.
He's on the Emperor's side.
利根川 初めて熟考
For the first time,
Tonegawa thinks hard.
動きが止まる
He stops.
しった
カイジの気迫　会長の叱咤
Kaiji's spirit.
The director's rebuke.
この６戦目の重要性
The importance
of this 6th game!
どうだ 利根川
Come on, Tonegawa.
しびれたろ？この勝負で初めて
You're afraid for the
first time, aren't you?
有利な皇帝側とはいえ
負けられない勝負
Even though winning
is your advantage now,
you can't lose just yet...
負けることを許されない勝負
...because you're
on the Emperor's side.
負けることの恐れを 初めて
心中に感じる勝負なんだからな
For the first time now,
you can feel
the fear of losing!
利根川 提出
Tonegawa, places his card!
６戦目
１枚目のカード 出そろう
The first cards for
the game are laid.
引き分け　｢市民｣と｢市民｣
Draw.
Citizen with Citizen.
ふっ… そうだ　こうなる
Right.
That's how it goes.
恐れれば恐れるほど
人は無理をしない
The more one feels fear,
the less one goes all out.
堅い戦略に流れる
One would take
a safer choice.
先出しで表情を観察される１枚目
He wouldn't play the Emperor
for the 1st and 3rd key card...
そして３枚目に勝負カード
｢皇帝｣は出してこない
...because his opponent
can see his expression.
出すとすれば
俺が先にカードを置く
He'll only do it
when it's my turn...
...to deal for the
2nd and 4th card first.
２枚目か４枚目…
しかし ２枚目はすでに殺した
埋め込んだ
But I've already
killed the 2nd card!
I've buried it...
２枚目に
さい疑心という恐れ… 鬼を…
...with fear
and suspicion!
利根川は２枚目に
｢皇帝｣を通せない
Tonegawa's not playing
Emperor for the 2nd card!
俺は４戦に続けて５戦も
２枚目に｢奴隷｣を出した
For the 4th and 5th games,
I played Slave for the 2nd card.
２枚目が｢奴隷｣という印象を
利根川に植え付けたかった
I wanted him to have...
...the impression that
the 2nd card is a Slave!
利根川は恐れる
Tonegawa is afraid.
He thinks I'll deal
3 Slaves in a row...
よもや３度 続けてと思いながらも
もしかしたらという気持ちは
拭えない
...but there might
be something else.
ひたすら考え
利根川が出す結論は｢保留｣
He'll consider it properly and
he'll resolved to being reserved.
２枚目には
もう一度 ｢市民｣を出し 様子見
He'll deal the Citizen again
for the 2nd card, as a gauge.
一か八かなどしない
いや できないんだ
He won't take any chances.
No, he can't do it!
そうなれば３枚目は 先出しで
｢皇帝｣は切りがたいから
It'll be difficult
to play Emperor...
...as the 3rd card later
when he deals 1st.
勝負は４枚目
The deciding card will
then come in the 4th card!
利根川 考え続け
４分になろうかという時
Tonegawa contemplates...
And just before
4 minutes passes,
やっと選択
he finally chooses his card.
提出　カード 出そろう
He places it!
Both cards are out.
ここで勝てば
ほぼ勝てる｢皇帝｣を３戦残し
If he wins now,
and wins the remaining
three games on the Emperor side,
勝ち金の合計も700万！
he'll gain a
total of 7 million!
2000万とはいわないが
1000万は完全に視野に…
20 million is too far fetched
but 10 million is within reach.
勝て　勝って道を…
Win this! And open the
way to a great victory!
大勝の道を開け！
カイジは｢市民｣
Kaiji chose Citizen.
どうだ？市民だろ お前も
Well? You've chosen
Citizen too, right?
Huh?
カイジ君 実によく分かるよ
I know you well, Kaiji.
私には君が何を考え
その｢市民｣に至ったか
I know what was on your mind
when you picked Citizen.
そして それはほぼ正しい
I must say that
you were almost right.
このＥカードにおける
定石のような考えかもしれぬ
You almost grasped the formula
to this game of E-Card.
しかし 残念ながら
Unfortunately...
その定石という地点が
ギャンブルでは最も浅はかなのだ
That formula is the last
thing you need in a gamble!
利根川 ２枚目に｢皇帝｣を通す
Tonegawa played Emperor
for his 2nd card!
バ… バカな… どうして？
N-No way! Why?
２枚目に｢皇帝｣は通せない
通せないはずなのに…
He can't play Emperor
for the 2nd card!
I was certain it was
impossible, and yet...
Then... go!
では ゴー
このＥカードに
必勝法のようなものはない
There's no sure-win
strategy in E-Card.
あるとすれば
勝つ確率を高める何かだが
Learning the chances
of winning in E-Card...
それは一朝一夕で
たどり着くようなものではない
...is not something
you can learn in a day.
蓄積なのだ　長年の経験のな
It is all about
years of experience.
しかし ビギナーは
すぐそれを手にしようとする
However, beginners always
fail to see that.
いや つかんだような気になり
掲げたがるのだ
They assume that they've
understood the game well.
確信めいたものを
So full of confidence.
そんな確信は付け焼き刃
Full of confidence, they simply
spring at the first opportunity...
しかし 本人にとっては
大変なひらめきに感じられ
あっさり それに沿おうとする
...without much thought.
疑い続けること…
不安であり続けることが
To have doubts and to
be alert at all times...
ギャンブルで生き残るために
最も必要な心構えなのに
...is the most important
quality in gambling.
素人ほど すぐそれを捨てる
But amateurs forgo these details.
カイジ君が考えて
たどり着いた地点は
Kaiji, the level
which you've reached...
まだまだ理屈の領域にすぎん
...is still within
the realm of logic.
それではダメだ
肝心なのはその先
That's not enough.
The next step would be
crossing over...
理屈の上に乗って うごめく
互いの感情だ
...and reading
your opponent's feelings.
感情？
そうだ
Feelings...
That's right.
カイジ君は理屈で止まり
感情へは踏み込まない
You stopped at logic.
You did not step into
the realm of feelings.
それでは勝てぬ
勝てるはずがない
There's no way you
can win like that.
逆に こちらから見た
カイジ君の感情は丸見えだ
Your emotions are
crystal clear to me, Kaiji.
楽すぎる勝負
This is too easy.
いや 唯一 苦労した点といえば
If I may add,
my greatest challenge...
カイジ君が私に期待する反応を
...is not to show the expression
you expect from me.
つつがなくして見せることくらい
つまり 悩んでいるふりを
することに
In other words, I had to
put on a front.
正直 一番骨を折った
I had to act as if I'm
thinking properly to choose.
カイジ ６戦目
10ミリの負けにより
In the 6th game, Kaiji lost 10mm,
making it a total of 24 mm!
針の合計は24ミリ
鼓膜までの猶予 ６ミリ
He has 6 mm left!
そして残り６試合
And exactly 6 games left.
あと６ミリ　６戦…
6 more mm
and 6 games left...
カイジ様
次のベット 賭けの距離は？
Mr. Kaiji,
what's your next bet?
カイジ様
Mr. Kaiji...
１…
1.
ええ？おいおい よせよ
Hey, stop that.
カイジ君の最低の針の距離は
２だったんじゃないのかい？
I thought your
minimum bet was 2?
ほんのちょっと前
人の忠告を無視して
Just a while ago, you
ignored people's advice.
２張っておいて もう降参か
Now you're giving up?
ダメなのか やっぱり…
Now it's really hopeless!
ふふ… まあいい
カイジ君が１だと言うのなら
Well, okay.
We'll respect that.
それは尊重せんとな
If you insist,
then 1 it shall be.
おい
- Hey.
- Yes.
では 続けるか
Let's continue then.
今度はカイジ君が皇帝側
Now it's your turn
to be the Emperor.
始めよう
Let's begin.
教えてやろうか １つだけ
Allow me to explain...
なぜカイジ君が敗れ 私が勝つか…
...why you will lose
and I will win, Kaiji.
このＥカードは心理戦
E-Card is a
psychological game.
そうカイジ君は
考えているようだが 実は違う
In reality, it's very different
from what you think.
そんなことより
はるかに勝利に近づく道がある
There's a faster method to win.
それは見る力
見る？
And that is the ability to see.
See?
相手が動揺しているかどうかを
見抜く
How to see through
your opponent's weakness.
単純で直接的な人を観察する能力
Simply put, the power
to observe others.
つまり 皇帝側は｢皇帝｣
Which means, Emperor
in the Emperor side.
奴隷側は｢奴隷｣
Slave in Slave.
この勝負カードを出した時の
相手の心の震えを
To win, you have to
read the opponent's mind...
観察する力が問われている
...at the moment of truth.
ふふふ… ｢何をバカなことを｣
"What on earth
are you talking about?"
"If that were possible,
it'd be too easy."
｢それができれば苦労しない｣
って顔だな
ところが経験を積めば
それほど難しいことではない
That's what it says on your face.
But in fact, it's not difficult.
例えばカイジ君の場合
勝負カードを出す時
For example, Kaiji,
in your case,
you stoop forward slightly
when playing a key card.
通常より若干 前傾が深くなる
さらに出した後の目線の動き
残したカードの持ち方
After you've decided,
your eye movement,
your style of holding
your remaining cards,
首の据わり 口元
your neck position,
the shape of your mouth...
眉の表情 肩 ひじ
the arch of your brows,
your shoulders,
elbows and
many other areas...
ほかにも いくらでもあるが
要するに告白しているんだ
They speak
like a confession.
口に出さねど体中で
Your body language
says it all.
隠しきれない　感情は決して
隠しきれるものではない
It's impossible for you to hide
your emotions in particular.
人というのは感情の器
Humans are containers
for emotions.
常に満々とした水
They filled up to
the brim like water.
ゆらゆらとした感情を
たたえている
That emotion will spill with
a slight movement of the heart.
その感情は
ちょっとした心の動きで
たやすく あふれる
器が小さいほど いびつなほど
感情はあふれやすい
In a person of lower calibre,
it would spill out faster.
そしてそれは
すぐに どうにかなるものではない
And it's not something
you can rectify immediately.
経験が必要なのだ
Experience is essential.
一朝一夕で感情は隠せん
You can't hide your
feelings in a day...
よって カイジ君は勝ち得ない
So you're bound
to lose, Kaiji.
バカな… もしそうなら
俺が先にカードを出す時は全滅
No way. If that's true,
then I've have lost everything
when I started first.
すべて看破されるって
ことじゃねえか
He'd have
seen through everything!
ふざけるな
Don't take me for a fool!
That's not true!
そんなわけない　あるはずがない
It's ridiculous.
He's bluffing. It's his strategy!
これはヤツのハッタリ 戦略…
だまされるな
I'm not falling for that!
くそっ
Darn it!
In the 7th game,
Kaiji played the Emperor.
７戦目　カイジ あえて
１枚目に｢皇帝｣を提出
Well? Try reading this!
どうだ　見抜いてみろ
If you can, that is!
見抜けるものなら…
しかし利根川 あっさり提出
But Tonegawa played calmly.
利根川 ｢奴隷｣
Tonegawa, Slave!
Looks like he saw through
Kaiji's plan!
カイジの考えを
見透かしたかのように…
カイジ 皇帝側でも勝てず５連敗
Kaiji lost on
the Emperor side.
5 straight losses!
８戦目
また１ミリ張っての８戦目
The 8th game.
The 8th game with yet
another wager of 1 mm.
バカな　バカな…
こんなことってあるか？
It can't be... It can't be!
Such things don't exist.
どうしてこんなことが？
How can this be?!
もはや完全に疑心暗鬼のカイジ
Kaiji is full of suspicion.
となれば そう簡単に
｢皇帝｣は通せない
He was unable to
play the Emperor card.
１枚目　２枚目
1st card, 2nd card, 3rd card...
３枚目　｢市民｣を出して引き分け
All Citizens and draws.
４枚目　二者択一の勝負
4th card.
He's left with one
out of 2 choices.
追い詰められる
何てこと… この状況は
What is this?!
I planned to trap
Tonegawa like this, but...
俺が利根川に
してやりたかったのに 逆…
くそっ
Darn it!
カイジ 利根川　共に｢市民｣
Kaiji and Tonegawa
both dealt Citizens.
４枚目も引き分け
All four cards were draws.
残るカードは カイジ ｢皇帝｣
The cards remaining:
Kaiji has Emperor.
利根川 ｢奴隷｣
Tonegawa has Slave.
つまりカードを出すまでもなく
There's no need
to reveal the cards.
利根川の勝ち
It is Tonegawa's win.
カイジ 本来
圧倒的に有利な皇帝側でも負け
Being on the Emperor Side
didn't benefit Kaiji at all!
泥沼　６連敗
Burdened with 6 straight losses!
念のために言っておこう
I'd like to remind you...
もし それを外そうとしても
The metalwork is special.
You won't succeed in removing it.
残念ながら その金具は特殊でな
特別の工具で分解する以外
外す すべはない
You need special
equipment to do that.
それでも
強引に外そうとした場合は
If you try removing it
by force,
このリモコンのアラームが鳴る
the alarm will go
off in this remote control.
外させんよ
こちらからすれば その耳は人質
And it'd alert us.
That ear is a
hostage for us.
勝手はさせん
今は貸してやっているだけだ
You can't do as
you please with it.
We're only lending
it to you now.
勝負がつけば その聴力は
Once the match ends,
that ear is ours!
頂く
Drill, drill, drill...
残すは４戦　そして…
4 games remain.
And...
鼓膜までの猶予も４ミリ
4 mm before reaching
the ear drum!
ダメ… 疑いようもない
No, there's no doubt about it!
もうこれは偶然でも
ハッタリでもない
This is neither a
coincidence nor a bluff.
この男は本当に分かるんだ
This guy really knows...
俺の出したカードが
勝負カードか否か
...whether I'm playing
the key card or not.
異能… 異能の観察眼
Extraordinary...
An extraordinary
power of observation.
まさに悪魔だ　悪魔じみている
He's like a devil.
Just like a devil.
あの的中率は
That level of observation is
beyond human ability.
とっくに人間の域を超えている
人の心の震え 動揺を見抜く天才…
He's a genius.
He can see people's hearts.
鬼…
A devil.
とてもかなわない
見透かされる　すべて…
I can't beat him.
He sees everything clearly.
Everything...
俺の心はすべて…
My mind... Everything!
勝てない　勝てるわけがない
I can't win!
It's impossible to win!
俺が唯一 勝てる可能性があるのは
Winning the last game as
Emperor is my last chance.
皇帝側の最終戦
次の９戦目だけ
The 9th game next.
９戦目を負けたら
針は間違いなく４ミリ進む
If he loses the 9th game,
the needle will extend 4mm.
合計 30ミリ
A total of 30 mm.
鼓膜に至る！
It's reaching his eardrum!
分かっとるな　ここだぞ
Do you understand?
It's here.
ここを勝ちさえすれば
あとは問題なくなる
If you win here,
there'll be no problems later.
気を緩めるなよ
Don't let your guard down.
分かっております
I understand.
せっかく夜更かしをしてるんだ
I stayed up
all night for this.
ここまで来たら
ぜひ カイジ君の絶叫を聞きたい
Since we're here,
I want to hear Kaiji's screams!
もっとも その声も
カイジ君の耳には
Oh well, the scream will only
半分しか届かないだろうがな
reach half of Kaiji's ears though.
９戦目　カイジが皇帝側で戦う
最後の試合
The 9th game. The last
round Kaiji plays as Emperor.
あとは勝ちがたい
奴隷側だけが残る
He's left with playing on
the Slave side after this.
この１戦 勝つか負けるかで
天国と地獄
Kaiji's fate hangs upon
the win or loss of this game.
勝てば生き残り
負ければ破滅…
Win and survive.
Lose and die!
破壊する
Destruction!
わずか１ミリでも届けば
器官を殺す
If it reaches even 1 mm closer,
the eardrum gets destroyed!
突破口を見いだせるか
カイジ
Will Kaiji find a solution?!
次回 ｢限界｣
Next, Limit.